Let's just start by looking at some great photographs.
دعونا نبدأ بمشاهدة بعض الصور الرائعة.
This is an icon of National Geographic,
هذه الصورة تعتبرالأيقونة للناشوينال جيوغرافيك
an Afghan refugee taken by Steve McCurry.
لفتاة لاجئة أفغانية التقطها ستيف ماكيري
But the Harvard Lampoon is about to come out
ولكن هارفرد لامبون (مجلة مضحكة) على وشك الخروج
with a parody of National Geographic,
محاكاة ً للناشوينال جيوغرافيك
and I shudder to think what they're going to do to this photograph.
مؤمناً بأني أعلم بماذا سيفكرون في العمل بمثل هذه الصورة
Oh, the wrath of Photoshop.
أوه، غضب الفوتوشوب
This is a jet landing at San Francisco, by Bruce Dale.
هذه طائرة تحل في سان فرانسيسكو التقطها بروس دييل
He mounted a camera on the tail.
ثبت الكاميرا على الذيل
A poetic image for a story on Tolstoy, by Sam Abell.
صورة شاعرية لقصة تولستوي بواسطة سام آبيل
Pygmies in the DRC, by Randy Olson.
البجميز (الأقزام) في الـ دي آر سي بواسطة راندي أولسون
I love this photograph because it reminds me
أحب هذه الصورة لأنها تذكرني
of Degas' bronze sculptures of the little dancer.
بالتمثال البرونزي "الراقصة الصغيرة" لديغاز
A polar bear swimming in the Arctic, by Paul Nicklen.
الدب القطبي يسبح في المحيط الأطلسي بواسطة بول نيكلن
Polar bears need ice to be able to move back and forth --
الدب القطبي يحتاج للثلج للسباحة للأمام والخلف
they're not very good swimmers --
لأنهم ليسوا سباحين مهرة
and we know what's happening to the ice.
ونحن نعلم مالذي يحصل للجليد.
These are camels moving across the Rift Valley in Africa,
وهذه صورة للجمال يقطعون وادي الرفت في أفريقيا
photographed by Chris Johns.
الصورة بواسطة كريس جونز
Shot straight down, so these are the shadows of the camels.
الصورة من الأعلى تماماً، لذا فهذه ظلال الجمال
This is a rancher in Texas, by William Albert Allard,
هذه مزرعة مواشي في تكساس، بواسطة وليام آلبرت آلارد
a great portraitist.
بورتريه رائع
And Jane Goodall, making her own special connection,
و جين جودويل، تصنع علاقاتها الخاصة
photographed by Nick Nichols.
صورة بواسطة نيك نيوكلاس
This is a soap disco in Spain, photographed by David Alan Harvey.
وهذه صورة ديسكو الصابون في اسبانيا بواسطة ديفيد آلن هارفي
And David said that there was lot of weird stuff
وقال ديفيد أنه هناك الكثير من الأمور الغريبة
happening on the dance floor.
تحصل على أرضية الرقص
But, hey, at least it's hygienic.
ولكن على الأقل الأرضية معقمة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
These are sea lions in Australia doing their own dance,
وهؤلاء أسود بحرية في استراليا يقوموم برقصتهم الخاصة
by David Doubilet.
بواسطة ديفيد دوبيليت
And this is a comet, captured by Dr. Euan Mason.
وهذا مذنب، ملتقط بواسطة إيوان مايسن
And finally, the bow of the Titanic, without movie stars,
وأخيراً، مقدمة التيتانك بدون الممثلين
photographed by Emory Kristof.
أُلتقطت بواسطة إيموري كريسوف
Photography carries a power that holds up
التصوير يحتوي على طاقة في التحمل
under the relentless swirl of today's saturated, media world,
تحت هذه الضوضاء والتشعب في عالم الميديا
because photographs emulate the way
لأن الصور تمهد الطريق
that our mind freezes a significant moment.
لأن أدمغتنا تجمد اللحظات العظيمة
Here's an example.
هذا مثال
Four years ago, I was at the beach with my son,
منذ أربع سنوات ذهبت إلى الشاطيء مع ابني
and he was learning how to swim
وكان حينها يتعلم السباحة للتو
in this relatively soft surf of the Delaware beaches.
في شواطىء ديلاوير الناعمة نسبياً
But I turned away for a moment, and he got caught into a riptide
لوهلة سهيت عنه حتى علق في دوامة بحرية
and started to be pulled out towards the jetty.
وبدأت تسحبه
I can stand here right now and see,
لم استطع الوقوف والمشاهدة
as I go tearing into the water after him,
بل قفزت خلفه في الماء
the moments slowing down and freezing into this arrangement.
بدأت الدقائق في التمهل والتجمد أمام هذا الموقف
I can see the rocks are over here.
استطيع الآن تخيل الصخور بجانبنا
There's a wave about to crash onto him.
وكانت هناك الموج قادم للارتطام به
I can see his hands reaching out,
استطيع مشاهدة يده تحاول الوصول
and I can see his face in terror,
واستطيع رؤية وجه ممتلأ بالخوف
looking at me, saying, "Help me, Dad."
ينظر إلي ويقول "أبي ساعدني"
I got him. The wave broke over us.
وصلت إليه، واصطدمت بنا الموجة
We got back on shore; he was fine.
رجعنا للشاطىء، وكان بخير
We were a little bit rattled.
كنا نوعاً ما مرعوبين ومتعبين
But this flashbulb memory, as it's called,
ولكن الذاكرة الضوئية اللحظية .. هكذا تُسمى
is when all the elements came together to define
هي التي تجمع جميع هذه العناصر لكي تُعرف
not just the event, but my emotional connection to it.
ليس فقط الحدث، إنما المشاعر المرتبطة به.
And this is what a photograph taps into
وهذا ما تضيفه الصورة وتتميز به
when it makes its own powerful connection to a viewer.
عندما تستطيع التواصل مع المشاهد بطريقة قوية
Now I have to tell you,
والآن علي إخباركم
I was talking to Kyle last week about this,
كنت أتحدث مع كايل عن هذا الموضوع
that I was going to tell this story.
أني كنت سأخبركم بهذه القصة
And he said, "Oh, yeah, I remember that too!
فقال لي "نعم أني أتذكر تلك القصة كذلك"
I remember my image of you
أتذكر صورتي التي شكلتها عنك
was that you were up on the shore yelling at me."
أنك كنت على الشاطىء وكنت تصرخ عليّ
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I thought I was a hero.
ظننت بأني بطل خارق
So,
فهذا ..
this represents -- this is a cross-sample of
يمثل ، نموذج عن
some remarkable images taken by some of the world's greatest photojournalists,
بعض الصور الرائعة الملتقطة بواسطة أعظم المصورين
working at the very top of their craft --
يعملون على أعلى مقدمة طائرتهم
except one.
عدا واحدة.
This photograph was taken by Dr. Euan Mason
هذه الصورة التقطت بواسطة د. إيوان مايسون
in New Zealand last year,
في نيوزلندا السنة الماضية
and it was submitted and published in National Geographic.
وتم نشرها ووضعها في " الناشيونال جيوغرافيك "
Last year, we added a section to our website called "Your Shot,"
في السنة الماضية وضعنا خانة جديدة في الموقع تسمى "صورتك"
where anyone can submit photographs for possible publication.
من خلالها يستطيع أي أحد وضع صورة التقطها ولربما تكون صالحة للنشر
And it has become a wild success,
وكان نجاحاً عظيماً
tapping into the enthusiast photography community.
في الدخول نحو مجتمع التصوير والمصورين المتفائلين
The quality of these amateur photographs
ونوعية الجودة في صور هؤلاء المصورين الهواة
can, at times, be amazing.
يمكن أن تكون في أوقات ما مذهلةً جداً.
And seeing this reinforces, for me,
ومشاهدة كل هؤلاء المصورين ,,, بالنسبة لي
that every one of us has at least one or two
أن في كل واحد منا هناك واحد أو اثنان
great photographs in them.
من المصويرن العظام فينا.
But to be a great photojournalist,
ولكن أن تكون مصور جيد
you have to have more than just one or two
يجب أن يكون لديك أكثر من واحد أو اثنان
great photographs in you.
من المصورين الماهرين فيك
You've got to be able to make them all the time.
يجب عليك أن تكون جميعهم في كل الأوقات
But even more importantly,
ولكن الأهم من ذلك
you need to know how to create a visual narrative.
يجب عليك أن تتمكن من خلق محرك بصري
You need to know how to tell a story.
يجب عليك أن تتمكن من قص حكاية
So I'm going to share with you some coverages
لذلك سأشارككم ببعض التغطيات
that I feel demonstrate the storytelling power of photography.
الصور فيها حكت الحكاية بقوة
Photographer Nick Nichols went to document
المصور نيك نيكولاس ذهب لتغطية
a very small and relatively unknown wildlife sanctuary
محمية صغيرة نسبياً لمنطقة برية
in Chad, called Zakouma.
في التشاد، تدعى زاكوما
The original intent was to travel there
الفكرة الأساسية كانت للسفر هناك
and bring back a classic story of diverse species,
وإحضار قصة كلاسيكية عن التنوع بين المخلوقات
of an exotic locale.
عن طبيعة مختلفة،
And that is what Nick did, up to a point.
وهذا ما فعله نيك للآن.
This is a serval cat.
هذا قط سيرفال
He's actually taking his own picture,
في الحقيقة هو يأخذ صور لنفسه
shot with what's called a camera trap.
صُور بما يسمى الكاميرا الفخ
There's an infrared beam that's going across,
وهذا ضوء أحمر لا مرئي يقطع المسافة
and he has stepped into the beam and taken his photograph.
وهو تجاوز ودخل في الضوء الأحمر ليأخذ صوره
These are baboons at a watering hole.
وهؤلاء قردة البابون في حفرة مائية.
Nick -- the camera, again, an automatic camera
نيك والكاميرا من جديد .. كاميرا إلكترونية
took thousands of pictures of this.
أخذ آلاف الصور من هذه اللقطة
And Nick ended up with a lot of pictures
وانتهى نيك بالكثير من الصور
of the rear ends of baboons.
من خلفيات قردة البابون
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
A lion having a late night snack --
وهذا أسد يتناول وجبة خفيفة ليلية
notice he's got a broken tooth.
لاحظوا لديه سن مكسور
And a crocodile walks up a riverbank toward its den.
وهذا تمساح يتجه من النهر إلى مأواه
I love this little bit of water
أحب هذه القطرات الصغيرة من الماء
that comes off the back of his tail.
التي على آخر ذيله
But the centerpiece species of Zakouma are the elephants.
ولكن الحيوان الرئيسي في زاكوما هي الفيلة
It's one of the largest intact herds in this part of Africa.
هذا واحد من القطعان الكاملة والسليمة في هذا الجزء من أفريقيا
Here's a photograph shot in moonlight,
وهذه صورة التقطت في ضوء القمر
something that digital photography has made a big difference for.
شيء مُمكن اليوم بسبب الفرق الكبير الذي جاء به التصوير الرقمي
It was with the elephants that this story pivoted.
والقصة هنا محورها فيل
Nick, along with researcher Dr. Michael Fay,
نيك مع الباحث الدكتور مايكل فاي
collared the matriarch of the herd.
طوقا الأنثى الحاكمة في القطيع
They named her Annie,
وسموها آني
and they began tracking her movements.
وبدأوا في متابعة خطواتها وتحركاتها
The herd was safe within the confines of the park,
القطيع كان بسلامة وأمان في أسوار الحديقة
because of this dedicated group of park rangers.
بسبب هؤلاء الذين يحمون الحديقة
But once the annual rains began,
ولكن متى بدأ المطر الموسمي
the herd would begin migrating to feeding grounds outside the park.
يبدأ القطيع في التحرك إلى خارج الحديقة المحمية للبحث عن غذاء
And that's when they ran into trouble.
وهناك عندما وقعت لهم المشاكل
For outside the safety of the park were poachers,
لأن الحماية خارج الحديقة المحمية كانت ضئيلة
who would hunt them down only for the value of their ivory tusks.
وهناك من سيصطاد الفيلة للحصول على العاج
The matriarch that they were radio tracking,
وتلك الأنثى الأم الحاكمة التي كانوا يراقبونها
after weeks of moving back and forth, in and out of the park,
بعد آسابيع من الخروج والعودة للحديقة المحمية
came to a halt outside the park.
توقفت خارج المحمية
Annie had been killed, along with 20 members of her herd.
آني قتلت مع 20 فيلاً من القطيع
And they only came for the ivory.
وجاءوا فقط من أجل العاج
This is actually one of the rangers.
وهذا أحد الحراس
They were able to chase off one of the poachers and recover this ivory,
وقد تمكنوا من اللحاق بأحد القتلة وأخذ العاج منهم
because they couldn't leave it there,
لم يستطيعوا تركه هناك
because it's still valuable.
لأنه كان غالياً
But what Nick did was he brought back
ولكن مالذي فعله نيك هو أنه أحضر معه
a story that went beyond the old-school method
قصة تجاوزت تلك القصص التي على نهج المدرسة
of just straight, "Isn't this an amazing world?"
والتي تهدف للقول فقط ، "أليس هذا العالم مذهل؟"
And instead, created a story that touched our audiences deeply.
ولكنه خلق قصة تلامس الجمهور بعمق
Instead of just knowledge of this park,
بدلاً من فقط إدلاء معلومات عن الحديقة المحمية
he created an understanding and an empathy
فهو خلق الفهم والتعاطف
for the elephants, the rangers and the many issues
لهذه الفيلة .. للحراس وللقضايا الأخرى
surrounding human-wildlife conflicts.
التي تحيط بالحياة البرية والصراعات
Now let's go over to India.
والآن لنذهب للهند.
Sometimes you can tell a broad story in a focused way.
أحياناً باستطاعتك أن تخير قصة عامة بشكل مركز
We were looking at the same issue that Richard Wurman
كنا نبحث في نفس القضية تحدث فيها ريتشارد ورمان
touches upon in his new world population project.
التي تحدث فيها عن مشروع العالم الجديد للسكان
For the first time in history,
لأول مرة في التاريخ
more people live in urban, rather than rural, environments.
أغلب البشر يعيشون في المناطق الحضرية لا النائية. البيئات
And most of that growth is not in the cities,
وأغلب النمو ليس في المدن
but in the slums that surround them.
ولكن في الاحياء الفقيرة التي حواليها
Jonas Bendiksen, a very energetic photographer,
جوناس بينديكسين، مصور نشيط جداً
came to me and said,
أتى لي وقال
"We need to document this, and here's my proposal.
"نحتاج لتوثيق هذا، وهذه هو اقتراحي:
Let's go all over the world and photograph every single slum around the world."
دعونا نذهب في جميع أنحاء العالم ، وتصوير كل واحد الأحياء الفقيرة في جميع أنحاء العالم. "
And I said, "Well, you know, that might be a bit ambitious for our budget."
وقلت : "حسنا ، كما تعلمون ، لربما يمكن أن يكون طموحاً قليلاً لميزانيتنا."
So instead, what we did was
بدلا من ذلك ما قمنا به هو ،
we decided to, instead of going out and doing what would result
بدلا من الخروج والقيام بما من شأنه أن يؤدي
in what we'd consider sort of a survey story --
في ما كنا النظر في نوع من قصة المسح ،
where you just go in and see just a little bit of everything --
حيث يمكنك الذهاب فقط في والنظر فقط قليلا على كل شيء ،
we put Jonas into Dharavi,
وضعنا جوناس في دارافي
which is part of Mumbai, India,
وهو جزء من بومباي ، الهند
and let him stay there, and really get into
والسماح له بالبقاء هناك وحقا في الحصول على
the heart and soul of this really major part of the city.
قلب وروح هذا حقا جزءا كبيرا من المدينة.
What Jonas did was not just go and do a surface look
ما فعله جوناس لم يكن فقط الذهاب وألقى نظرة سطحية على
at the awful conditions that exist in such places.
الأوضاع المروعة الموجودة في مثل هذه الأماكن.
He saw that this was a living and breathing and vital part
ولكنه نظر إلى المكان وكأنه مكان حيوي يعيش ويتنفس ..
of how the entire urban area functioned.
ونظر إلى الحياة المدنية التي تقطن تلك المنطقة بالكامل
By staying tightly focused in one place,
بالإنتظار والتركيز في مكان واحد،
Jonas tapped into the soul and the enduring human spirit
نفذ جوناس داخل النفس والروح الإنسانية
that underlies this community.
الكامنة في هذا المجتمع.
And he did it in a beautiful way.
ولقد فعلها بطريقة جميلة.
Sometimes, though, the only way to tell a story is with a sweeping picture.
بعض الأحيان، تكون الطريقة الوحيدة لحكي قصة هي صورة شاملة.
We teamed up underwater photographer Brian Skerry
لقد كونّا فريقاً تحت الماء مع المصور براين سكيري
and photojournalist Randy Olson
والمصور الصحفي راندي أولسون
to document the depletion of the world's fisheries.
لتوثيق إستنزاف مصائد الأسماك في العالم.
We weren't the only ones to tackle this subject,
لم نكن الوحيدين الذين تطرقنا لهذا الموضوع،
but the photographs that Brian and Randy created
لكن الصور التي إلتقطها براين وراندي
are among the best to capture both the human
هي ضمن أفضل الصور الملتقطة لكلا البشر
and natural devastation of overfishing.
وإستنزاف الطبيعة والصيد الجائر.
Here, in a photo by Brian,
هنا، في صورة ملتقطها براين،
a seemingly crucified shark is caught up
على ما يبدو قرش مصلوب
in a gill net off of Baja.
في شبكة قبالة باجا.
I've seen sort of OK pictures of bycatch,
لقد رأيت نوع من الصور الجيدة عرضياً،
the animals accidentally scooped up
تم صيد الحيوانات بلا قصد
while fishing for a specific species.
أثناء صيد حيوانات محددة.
But here, Brian captured a unique view
لكن هنا، إلتقط براين مشهداً فريداَ
by positioning himself underneath the boat
بوضعه نفسه تحت القارب
when they threw the waste overboard.
بينما يلقون بالنفايات من القارب.
And Brian then went on to even greater risk
ثم مضى براين لمخاطرة أكبر
to get this never-before-made photograph
لتحقيق الصورة التي لم يفعلها أحد من قبل
of a trawl net scraping the ocean bottom.
للشباك التي تجرف قاع المحيط.
Back on land, Randy Olson photographed
رجوعاَ إلى الأرض، صوّر راندي أولسون
a makeshift fish market in Africa,
سوق مخلفات السمك في أفريقيا،
where the remains of filleted fish were sold to the locals,
حيث بقايا الأسماك المقطعة يتم بيعها للسكان المحليين،
the main parts having already been sent to Europe.
والتي تكون أجزاؤها الرئيسية قد أرسلت إلى أوروبا.
And here in China, Randy shot a jellyfish market.
وهنا في الصين، صور راندي سوق قناديل البحر.
As prime food sources are depleted,
لأن مصادر الغذاء الأساسية نضبت،
the harvest goes deeper into the oceans
الصيد الجائر يذهب في أعماق المحيطات
and brings in more such sources of protein.
ويجلب المزيد من مثل مصادر البروتين هذه.
This is called fishing down the food chain.
يسمى هذا الصيد أسفل السلسلة الغذائية.
But there are also glimmers of hope,
لكن هناك بصيص من الأمل أيضاً،
and I think anytime we're doing a big, big story on this,
وأعتقد أننا في كل وقت نقوم بقصة كبيرة للغاية حول هذا،
we don't really want to go
فأننا لا نريد الذهاب بالفعل
and just look at all the problems.
وأن ننظر فقط لكل هذه المشاكل.
We also want to look for solutions.
نحتاج أيضاَ أن نتطلع إلى حلول.
Brian photographed a marine sanctuary in New Zealand,
صور براين محمية بحرية في نيوزلندا
where commercial fishing had been banned --
حيث تم منع الصيد التجاري،
the result being that the overfished species have been restored,
وكانت النتائج أن الأسماك المفرط صيدها قد تم إستعادتها،
and with them a possible solution for sustainable fisheries.
ومع ذلك حلّ محتمل للصيد المستدام.
Photography can also compel us to confront
التصوير أيضاَ يمكن أن يجبرنا على مواجهة
issues that are potentially distressing and controversial.
قضايا يحتمل أن تكون مؤلمة ومثيرة للجدل.
James Nachtwey, who was honored at last year's TED,
جيمس ناشتوي، الذي تم تكريمه العام الماضي في تيد،
took a look at the sweep of the medical system
ألقى نظرة على النظام الطبي الكسيح
that is utilized to handle the American wounded coming out of Iraq.
المطبق للتعامل مع الجرحى الأمريكيين القادمين من العراق.
It is like a tube where a wounded soldier enters on one end
إنه مثل الأنبوب حيث يدخل الجنود الجرحى في طرف
and exits back home, on the other.
ويخرجون، يرجعون الوطن، في الجانب الآخر.
Jim started in the battlefield.
بدأ جيم في ميدان المعركة.
Here, a medical technician tends to a wounded soldier
هنا، يميل مختص طبي تجاه جندي جريح
on the helicopter ride back to the field hospital.
في هلوكوبتر راجعين الى مستشفى الميدان.
Here is in the field hospital.
هنا مستشفى الميدان.
The soldier on the right has the name of his daughter
للجندي على اليمين أسم بنته
tattooed across his chest, as a reminder of home.
موشوم على صدره ليتذكر الوطن.
From here, the more severely wounded are transported
من هنا، يتم نقل الجرحى بشكل جدي
back to Germany, where they meet up with their families
إلى ألمانيا، حيث يقابلون أسرهم
for the first time.
لأول مرة.
And then back to the States to recuperate at veterans' hospitals,
ثم يرجعون إلى أمريكا لإستكمال العلاج في مستشفيات المحاربين القدامى
such as here in Walter Reed.
كما هو هنا في والتر ريد.
And finally, often fitted with high-tech prosthesis,
وختاماَ، وغالباَ يزودون بتكنلوجيا ترقيعية،
they exit the medical system and attempt
يخرجون من النظام الطبي ويحاولون
to regain their pre-war lives.
الرجوع لحياتهم ما قبل الحرب.
Jim took what could have been a straight-up medical science story
أخذ جيم ما قد يكون متابعة مباشرة لقصة علوم طبية
and gave it a human dimension that touched our readers deeply.
وإضاف إليها بعداَ إنسانياَ لامس القراء بعمق.
Now, these stories are great examples
الآن، هذه القصص هي أمثلة عظيمة
of how photography can be used
لكيف يمكن إستخدام التصوير
to address some of our most important topics.
لمخاطبة بعض أهم القضايا.
But there are also times when photographers
لكن هناك أيضاَ أوقات عندما يصادف المصور
simply encounter things that are, when it comes down to it,
ببساطة أشياء هي، عندما يأتي الأمر لذلك،
just plain fun.
فقط مجرد مرح.
Photographer Paul Nicklin traveled to Antarctica
المصور باول نيكلين سافر إلى القارة القطبية الجنوبية
to shoot a story on leopard seals.
لتصوير قصة حول الفقمة.
They have been rarely photographed, partly because they are considered
نادراَ ما كان يتم تصويرها ، جزئياَ بسبب انها تعتبر
one of the most dangerous predators in the ocean.
أحد أخطر الحيوانات المفترسة في البحار.
In fact, a year earlier, a researcher had been
في الواقع، قبل عام من ذلك قبضت أحداها
grabbed by one and pulled down to depth and killed.
باحثاَ وسحبته إلى الأعماق وقتلته.
So you can imagine Paul was maybe a little bit hesitant
لذا يمكنكم تخيل أن باول ربما كان متردداَ قليلاَ
about getting into the water.
بالنسبة للنزول إلى الماء.
Now, what leopard seals do mostly is, they eat penguins.
الآن، ما تفعله الفقمة غالباَ هو، انها تأكل البطاريق.
You know of "The March of the Penguins."
تعرفون " مسيرة البطاريق"
This is sort of the munch of the penguins.
والآن تعرفوا إلى إلتهام البطاريق
(Laughter)
(آآآآه)
Here a penguin goes up to the edge and looks out
هنا يذهب البطريق إلى الحافة ليتأكد
to see if the coast is clear.
وينظر إن كان الشاطئ آمناَ.
And then everybody kind of runs out and goes out.
ثم يجري الجميع خارج البحر هرباً.
But then Paul got in the water.
لكن باول دخل إلى الماء بدلا من ذلك .
And he said he was never really afraid of this.
وقال انه لم يكن خائفاَ حقاَ من هذا بتاتاَ.
Well, this one female came up to him.
حسناَ، هذه الأنثى ظهرت له.
She's probably -- it's a shame you can't see it in the photograph,
من المرجح انها -- من العيب أنكم لا تستطيعون رؤيتها في الصورة --
but she's 12 feet long.
لكن طولها 12 قدماَ.
So, she is pretty significant in size.
لذا فهي مميزة للغاية في الحجم.
And Paul said he was never really afraid,
وقال باول انه لم يكن خائفاَ بتاتاَ،
because she was more curious about him than threatened.
لأنها كانت أكثر فضولاَ حوله عن كونها تهديداَ.
This mouthing behavior, on the right,
هذا السلوك الفموي على اليمين
was really her way of saying to him, "Hey, look how big I am!"
كان حقاَ طريقة لتقول له، " أنت، أنظر كم أنا كبيرة!"
Or you know, "My, what big teeth you have."
أو كما تعلمون، " أنت، ما هو مدى كبر أسنانك."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Then Paul thinks that she simply took pity on him.
ثم يعتقد باول انها أشفقت عليه ببساطة.
To her, here was this big, goofy creature in the water
بالنسبة لها، كانت بهذا الكبر، مخلوق أحمق في الماء
that for some reason didn't seem to be interested
كان لسبب ما غير مهتم
in chasing penguins.
بمطاردة البطاريق.
So what she did was she started to bring penguins to him,
إذاَ ما فعلته كان أنها بدأت بجلب البطاريق إليه،
alive, and put them in front of him.
حية، وتقوم بوضعها أمامه.
She dropped them off, and then they would swim away.
لقد رمت بهم ثم يقومون بالسباحة بعيداَ.
She'd kind of look at him, like "What are you doing?"
وهي تنظر إليه، مثل " ماذا تفعل؟"
Go back and get them, and then bring them back
أذهب وأمسك بهم، وأحضرهم إلى هنا
and drop them in front of him.
وقم برميهم أمامي.
And she did this over the course of a couple of days,
وقد فعلت هذا طوال فترة عدة أيام
until the point where she got so frustrated with him
حتى وصلت للنقطة التي سئمت منه،
that she started putting them directly on top of his head.
ثم بدأت بوضعهم مباشرة على رأسه.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Which just resulted in a fantastic photograph.
ما نتج عنه صورة رائعة.
Eventually, though, Paul thinks that she just figured
في نهاية المطاف، يعتقد باول أنها توصلت إلى
that he was never going to survive.
أنه لن ينجو بتاتاَ.
This is her just puffing out, you know,
هذه نوع ما الطريقة التي تقوم بابعادهم،
snorting out in disgust.
تشخر بنوع من الإشمئزاز.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And lost interest with him, and went back to what she does best.
وفقدت الاهتمام به وعادت للقيام بما تحسن عمله
Paul set out to photograph a relatively
قرر باول تصوير مخلوق
mysterious and unknown creature,
غامض وغير معروف نسبياَ ،
and came back with not just a collection of photographs,
وعاد مع ليس فقط مجموعة من الصور،
but an amazing experience and a great story.
لكن أيضاَ تجربة مذهلة وقصة عظيمة.
It is these kinds of stories,
إنها مثل هذا النوع من القصص،
ones that go beyond the immediate or just the superficial
التي تذهب لأعمق من اللحظة الحالية أو تكون ظاهرية جداً،
that demonstrate the power of photojournalism.
لكي توضح قوة التصوير الصحفي
I believe that photography can make a real connection to people,
أنا أؤمن بأن التصوير يستطيع أن يتواصل مع البشر
and can be employed as a positive agent
وبإستطاعته أن يُجندنا لكي نكون أفراداً إيجابين
for understanding the challenges and opportunities
لكي نفهم التحديات والفرص
facing our world today.
في مواجهة عالمنا الحالي
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)